<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ZortaZert</title>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/rss.xml</link>
    <image>
      <title>ZortaZert</title>
      <url>/img/icons/chadoku.ico</url>
      <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/rss.xml</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Languages</title>
      <guid>language-learning.html</guid>
      <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/blog/language-learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 </pubDate>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Friday April 19th I started learning Russian more seriously. It has become a part of my daily routine. I probably started earlier however because I needed to know the Cyrllic first. This did not come easy but overtime with practice I got it a bit. It’s learning a new alphabet which is difficult. I still haven’t mastered it but I know the majority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used duolingo for school which was way better because you get unlimited lives and extra lessons for free. However there is no leaderboard and there are some features missing. I was able to develop a 22 day streak which is the highest streak I ever got.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://duolingo.com/users/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funny json I found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that Duolingo is good, however you also need a strong foundation in english. It repeats concepts over and over which is good for slow learners but not good if you already know something. Like I have practiced how to say the beginning of something at least 20 times and it’s not different at all. I think that would be better displayed as a concept which they show you instead of practicing over and over repetitively. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing I picked back up on is Anki cards. I downloaded an Anki deck scraped from duolingo and I have practiced that which should be good for me to know most spelling if not google will spell check me into the right place until I eventually get it. Even in English I still make some spelling mistakes so spelling will definitely be a big challenge. Biggest priority is to do Duolingo everyday because it is a solid 5 minutes of practice. However, I like to do anki additionally and that will take 4-8 minutes depending on how many words are scheduled to learn on a later date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing which helps me learn the letters of russian, reading and typing is typingclub I have picked up on. I originally used typingclub to learn english touch typing but now I am using it for russian and this is good to help with using the language practically. I think that this substantially helped me at learning the letters. I can type some letters and have started today to search for stuff in russian. Prior to this I figured out how to put russian on my old phone and have typed in Russian so it didn’t come right off the bat. On the phone it has great autocomplete but still I need to work on my grammar. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that learning russian everyday is pretty good to fill my days with some meaning it doesn’t take that long to do. Also, not everyday I must do Anki or typingclub, those just speed up the process. I already have some foundation in russian comprehension and can have basic conversations with people so the road to fluency will come for me a bit earlier. One thing I discovered is that I somehow bypassed future tense conjugations and have no clue how to do those for most cases. I can understand them when I hear them but I don’t know how to use them myself. I always say I will use the same conjugation in the end but in reality the complete word will actually change incredibly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I studied Spanish at school pretty seriously just by learning vocab and writing every other day and it has been very effective at improving my spanish. I am not at a conversational level but I can understand some Spanish and most importantly I can write spanish. I can say basic sentences. I find this pretty impressive considering I didn’t know Spanish 2 years ago. It’s also funny to analyze and try to comprehend the Spanish used in Better all Saul and understand some of it at first. I believe that I should work on Spanish over the summer by focusing on comprehension and listening to shows I watch in Spanish dub or with Spanish subtitles in order to focus on immersion. I know important conjugations and important vocab words but Spanish the way it’s spoken and written is rather difficult. I need to focus on that. Maybe if I move to a Spanish speaking country this skill will come in handy. I am better than most of my peers in class because I use the language as much as I can even though I am bad at it. I will most likely shift gears to typing russian at some point. An inspiration to me in this has been livakivi&amp;#39;s videos on him documenting his japanese learning. I want to try and document some of my language learning as well. Language learning is super fun and I plan on continuing. I have done more serious Russian learning for a month or so now. I started more seriously last year at the beginning of highschool learning Spanish and I have only continued since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Smash Bros Free</title>
      <guid>super-smash-bros-free.html</guid>
      <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/blog/super-smash-bros-free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 </pubDate>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If game good, game free (sketchy download links should not apply) ---me&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-18cb43c5bf&quot;&gt;Super Scratch Bros&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://scratch.mit.edu/projects/318927435/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the name says this is a scratch version of smash bros. You can play in your browser. Assuming you have internet access. If you want to save the game for offline access you can:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the see inside button or append &lt;code&gt;/editor&lt;/code&gt; to the link above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; on the top ribbon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;code&gt;Save to your computer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install scratch 3.0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; on the top ribbon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;code&gt;Load from your computer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way to get the .sb3 file is to use this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rebane2001/scratch-dl&quot;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-30961aa4d7&quot;&gt;Super Smash Flash and Super Smash Flash 2&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classics. Both Super Smash Flash and Super Smash Flash 2 can be found on https://supersmashflash.com. They can be played if you maraculously have flash in your browser, or through Ruffle on super smash flash 1, flashpoint and official download links on their website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;Super Smash Flash 2&quot;&gt;https://www.supersmashflash.com/play/ssf2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;Super Smash Flash 1&quot;&gt;https://www.supersmashflash.com/play/ssf1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-5f39884723&quot;&gt;Super Smash Land&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the best demakes in the history of fan demakes. Super Smash Land is a super smash bros in the gameboy art style. Free to play through the download link on the website&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://www.supersmashland.com/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-a13bdd6c96&quot;&gt;Link clickery 🖱&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;All Super Smash Bros games I am 95% sure (have not tested) can work in emulators. From the begining Super Smash Bros has placed an emphasis on the usage of an analog stick for many attacks and movements. Theorettically a keyboard should work but you can&amp;#39;t go 45 degrees. https://keyboard.gg/ aims to combat this by making keys assigned to 45 degree analog stick movements. Maybe similar functionality could be modded into emulators but for now I think you need a controller/analog stick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;System&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Emulator&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Super Smash Bros.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Rosalie241/RMG&quot;&gt;RMG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Super Smash Bros. Melee&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GameCube&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dolphin-emu.org/&quot;&gt;dolphin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Super Smash Bros. Brawl&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Wii&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dolphin-emu.org/&quot;&gt;dolphin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Super Smash Bros. for Nintendo 3DS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nintendo 3DS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://citra-emu.org/&quot;&gt;citra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Super Smash Bros. for Wii U&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Wii U&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cemu.info/&quot;&gt;cemu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Super Smash Bros. Ultimate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nintendo Switch&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ryujinx.org/&quot;&gt;ryujinx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eevee Evolutions</title>
      <guid>eveeevolutions.html</guid>
      <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/blog/eveeevolutions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 </pubDate>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Evee evolution speculation is happening right now and I would like to give my take on all the possible ones that could happen. Maybe I will draw one of the likely new Evee evolutions to come out. These are the ones that are available to work with:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bug&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Poison&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flying&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ground&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dragon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fighting&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ghost&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a lot of them I think are unlikely to happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-d659704a55&quot;&gt;IMPOSSIBLE TO HAPPEN (In my opinion)&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-1751a7ae1c&quot;&gt;Dragon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee doesn&amp;#39;t look like a lizard animal like most dragon types. Evee looks more like a combination of a dog and a cat. So dragon doesn&amp;#39;t fit in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-e20a7adb2c&quot;&gt;Steel&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee doesn&amp;#39;t look like a peice of metal, like most steel types. So once again just doesn&amp;#39;t fit in my opinion. At less somehow a peice of metal gets attached to it. Unlikely I think.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-a4f2b66833&quot;&gt;Fighting&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee is litterally a normal type. So if it evolved into a fighting type that would be weird because evee originally a normal type has a weakness towards fighting types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-f3ec817a7b&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee evolving into a ghost type would mean, a little cute evee death happened...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-681354eb29&quot;&gt;POSSIBLE TO HAPPEN!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-48562b537c&quot;&gt;Bug&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;An evee bug type would be pretty cool. The transformation from this soft puppy to an insect will be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-7215595bd7&quot;&gt;Poison&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee gaining the ability to release toxins or inject toxins either way would be epic. Possibly some stinger on the tail. However, they need to keep evee still cute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-f25c21608e&quot;&gt;Flying&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee growing wings would be interesting, given that evee has been firmly put on the ground all of it&amp;#39;s life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-7f78051bdf&quot;&gt;Rock&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evee freaking throwing rocks and having a tail made out of rocks will be very cool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-2950a19efe&quot;&gt;Ground&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;IDK what evee&amp;#39;s going to do by being a ground type.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fediverse review</title>
      <guid>fediverse.html</guid>
      <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/blog/fediverse.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 </pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-600b7bf711&quot;&gt;What is the fediverse?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fediverse is a lot of software such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mastodon_(software)&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PeerTube&quot;&gt;peertube&lt;/a&gt;and a lot more I will try and cover my experiences with different federation software I have used in this article. I find a new one of them everyday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of these federation programs have one thing in common, there are multiple servers that run the software independently from each other. Yet they still access one another as &lt;b&gt;one&lt;/b&gt;. Let&amp;#39;s say a peertube self hosted instance https://tube.tchncs.de is really cool with all of it&amp;#39;s creators and content but finds out about a another peertube instance called https://diode.zone. Imediatly https://tube.tchncs.de maintainer can let the instance on the front page and other parts of the website show videos from https://diode.zone. Useres on https://tube.tchncs.de can like, dislike, comment, view and do everything they want even though https://diode.zone is a completely different server then https://tube.tchncs.de. &lt;b&gt;But&lt;/b&gt; let&amp;#39;s say https://diode.zone stops moderation and now porn is overflooding the instance. Uh oh you might think! The server maintainer of https://tube.tchncs.de may not like that so he decides to immediatly close connections to https://diode.zone and continue to connect to other instances he likes. Now this isn&amp;#39;t even to say that a user on https://tube.tchncs.de can still visit https://diode.zone and watch videos and interact with there https://tube.tchncs.de account. Maybe your not a consumer but actually a content creator and are posting NSFW or highly mythical, not accepting of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_Spaghetti_Monster&quot;&gt;flying sphageti monster&lt;/a&gt;type of content. On peertube all you got to do is find a instance and read one that let&amp;#39;s you post whatever the hell you want and now you get to enjoy content posting freedome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see this federation stuff is &lt;b&gt;awesome&lt;/b&gt;. It has been adapted for all forms of social media of any kind. It&amp;#39;s so powerfule. No user can hate the platform because they get banned and multiple server owners are in control not just &lt;b&gt;one&lt;/b&gt; big corporation like google for YouTube. So hopefully you get my explination. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PeerTube&quot;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;is not the only fediverse thing out there. There are multiple others and I would like to talk about all that I know of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-8461ca79d4&quot;&gt;Peertube&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;PeerTube as the name suggest&amp;#39;s is similar in a way to something like YouTube. Just really nail&amp;#39;s down on the &lt;b&gt;You&lt;/b&gt; part. It&amp;#39;s a video platform which can do anything that youtube can in a more minimal and privacy respecting way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upload videos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upload livestreams&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upload whatever you want (Have to find a instance, but &lt;b&gt;yes&lt;/b&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like/dislike&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are also a lot of cool content creators on it. A lot of them not really well known but still make super cool stuff. Not just about tech or GNU/Linux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-f9d99d6e69&quot;&gt;Bad things:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From user experience I would say it looks really scarry, but don&amp;#39;t be scared. I am pretty sure that if you can read this article you have enouph ability to use peertube ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can not find a easy way to do publishing with it without actual software. However I believe they are not as much of a spyware like &lt;a href=&quot;https://lbry.ix.tc&quot;&gt;odysee.com&lt;/a&gt;is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-0f28eeb820&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is definitely a known in the category of FOSS chat clients as a great alternative to whatsapp, discord, skype and facebook/twiter messanger. Matrix is a federation software that handles many things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joining rooms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reaction emoticons&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating chat messages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groups/Spaces (Multiple chat rooms packaged together)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mentioning users&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Private chat&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;MULTIPLE CLIENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So matrix has everything. Maybe, your in a touph situation where you need to use a properietary software for chatting. Most likely there is a way for you to mirror the messages from the proprietary chat thing to matrix. You would just need to talk to the chat room owner if you can put in a bot there for the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that matrix has is a &lt;b&gt;lot&lt;/b&gt; of clients. You can deffinitly find a client that you like, suits your needs and is FOSS software. One thing to keep in mind that maybe you wouldn&amp;#39;t think of if you used proprietary chat stuff before is that everything you send in a room is &lt;b&gt;public&lt;/b&gt;. Anyone can grab out there screenshot tool or camera and take a snap at your message. However, this is not the case in private chats, since &lt;b&gt;encryption&lt;/b&gt; and the person your chatting to you probably trust not to leak stuff you send. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-1d917bee93&quot;&gt;Bad things&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are not a lot of none JS bloatware matrix clients. I geuss you don&amp;#39;t need to care about how bloated a FOSS peice of software like matrix is. But I think it&amp;#39;s nice to have a more minimal client. Minimal clients that I know of are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quaternion&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gomuks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matrixcli&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neochat&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mirage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nheko&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ement (emacs)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plenty to choose from but most all of them have there issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-44b0b0abeb&quot;&gt;Mastodon/Pleroma&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mastodon/Pleroma are a alternative to something like twitter or maybe in some cases reddit. They are both practically the same it&amp;#39;s just Mastodon forces you to have a smaller character limit. I think this has the benefits of helping yourself make sure to be really concise with what your talking about. I think of Mastodon/Pleroma as a place to discuss certain topics in a organized way and also a place to notify people about what your doing in life. Mastodon/Pleroma is are two really great peaces of software that work really well together and by themselves and other instances or stuff on federation. There is truly no excuse for people to continue using twitter. (I can&amp;#39;t think of one)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-490b406766&quot;&gt;Clients&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can obviously use whatever your instance that you chose uses in your web browser. But that&amp;#39;s really not cool and bloated. I would rather have my own app on my machine that I control. I also don&amp;#39;t want it to be bloated javascript.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The options from what I understand are not that many but okay. NOTE: I can not guarantee that all these work on pleroma. Most likely they do. If they don&amp;#39;t and you use pleroma consider reporting a issue on there repo asking for support :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toot (A python package for doing all things on mastodon.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mastodon.el (A mastodon/pleroma package for emacs.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BloatFE (Runs in browser but is very lightweight.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-c3b733dae3&quot;&gt;My video &amp;#34;Use Mastodon/Pleroma!&amp;#34;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tube.tchncs.de/w/fXS18zwhRBzPo1VkmJRamg&quot;&gt;Peertube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://lbry.ix.tc/@trueauracoral:a/Use-Mastodon:2&quot;&gt;librarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-7b7bef0434&quot;&gt;Invidious&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invidious is a very plain topic. The software works well and &lt;b&gt;you&lt;/b&gt; should use it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-925d463670&quot;&gt;My video &amp;#34;Use Invidious!&amp;#34;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tube.tchncs.de/w/e9MmjxwqnR7RnFaYtVueWg&quot;&gt;Peertube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://lbry.ix.tc/@trueauracoral:a/Use-Invidious%21:1&quot;&gt;librarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-5a5e946881&quot;&gt;Plume&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plume is a MD article posting place. It is supposed to work, I have a account there but it&amp;#39;s not letting me post articles without shrinking them into one big line. Other people have it all working. It seems like plume is still in early development. One day I think it will be really good. For now it&amp;#39;s usable but you may have issues with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-0d6ca096d9&quot;&gt;Fchan&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fchan is another software that&amp;#39;s a bit early in development but it definitely works! It is a FOSS image board that looks a lot like 4chan. It works well it&amp;#39;s just lacking in users. I asked 4chan why there still on proprietary 4chan, they said &amp;#34;All my friends are on it!&amp;#34; 4chan even decided to close the post! Absolutely horrible! Go use fchan (Fedderated channels).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to degoogle</title>
      <guid>degoogle.html</guid>
      <link>https://trueauracoral.github.io/blog/degoogle.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 </pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-9f6704f36d&quot;&gt;Google&amp;#39;s Popularity&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google is like a household name to a lot of people that use the computer. For the price of &lt;b&gt;0 DOLLARS&lt;/b&gt; the registered account gets access to free email. Email is essential for authenticating accounts, messaging freinds and a lot of things. So you need a email and you just turn to google. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remember being super young and someone brought up having a email. Saying:&amp;#34;You can&amp;#39;t make a google account without being over 13!&amp;#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought this was strange and wanted to see if this was true. Going to my computer I tried and was locked from making a account, just because I was 8 years old and not 13. What I didn&amp;#39;t know is all the information I just gave to google right the and there. I gave my real birth date, name, last name probably home address. &lt;b&gt;Everything&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now imagine this scenario with people actually use the google service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;org-5006d04d6f&quot;&gt;Google&amp;#39;s services&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;With google you get a LOT of services. Each and every one of them is proprietary. Each and everyone of them gives your data to google. I want in this article to go over them and show some good alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-80acb7ac51&quot;&gt;Gmail&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a tough cookie to get away from. A lot of privacy/GNU/Linux enthusiasts even use gmail. Email is not secure. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://anon.sx&quot;&gt;searx&lt;/a&gt;and find out why. So you might be thinking why not use gmail? All your messages go to google&amp;#39;s services as well as using proprietary software just to create a account. Even if you used proprietary software to create it a long time ago and are sitting nicely with a gmail drawer of emails in your email client. Your still having all your emails able to be read by google. That is not fun at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solution this is using a alternative mail service. There are a couple at the time of posting this article that I think are good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tormail&lt;/b&gt; is some sort of mail service managed in tor. I haven&amp;#39;t used it myself&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disroot&lt;/b&gt; is a public email service. All your emails could be read by disroot but at least disroot isn&amp;#39;t google. So far there aren&amp;#39;t any privacy claims against them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;matthewevan.xyz&lt;/b&gt;. Matthew Evan or MattMadness actually gave me a email that works online and on the phone through a web app. It also should work through a email client. Possibly you can ask him and he will grant you with a awesome email&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-181a0d93e0&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Youtube is terrible and I bet it will be a cause for the death of humanity. I covered out more reasons and how to switch from youtube to something else in this article: &lt;a href=&quot;https://odysee.com/@trueauracoral:a/do-not-use-youtube:b&quot;&gt;Do not use Youtube.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-024e9091a5&quot;&gt;G Suit&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;#39;s g suit is a set of office tools. A obvious and really great alternative to this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://[libreoffice&quot;&gt;https://[libreoffice&lt;/a&gt; Libreoffice docx exports to g suite products from my experience in the past were good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-c9c10b09e0&quot;&gt;Google&amp;#39;s Search Engine&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google is named by its search engine. The alternatives to google&amp;#39;s search engine are a LOT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Searx&lt;/b&gt;, I made a article on this already on how to set it up: &lt;a href=&quot;https://zortazert.codeberg.page/Blog/searx.html&quot;&gt;Search Engines (Searx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SearxNG&lt;/b&gt; is searx but more modern looking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Whoogle&lt;/b&gt; is basicly a google viewer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/b&gt; I only advise using duckduckgo if your on your phone and have no other option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-4d5863dbe0&quot;&gt;Google maps.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best alternative to it is not &lt;b&gt;waze&lt;/b&gt; that is literally also owned by google apparently. The best alternative is openstreetmaps. It for sure isn&amp;#39;t a perfect solution. But at least you will find yourself using googlemaps/waze less.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-f2eb51f01e&quot;&gt;Chrome Browser&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is absolutely no reason to use chrome. https://spyware.neocities.org/articles/chrome.html This article does a great job explaining how bad it is. There are very few browsers left out there that are decent even.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Qutebrowser&lt;/b&gt; is great with the only downside of it being that you need to know some basic vim keys to use it. However you should be able to just use your mouse for everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Otter-Browser&lt;/b&gt; In development but looks awesome&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ice-cat&lt;/b&gt; Best browser ever. Just you may need a regular browser for some things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-07c2964c41&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nextcloud does a lot of things but primarily its supposed to back up files and be a google alternative. https://github.com/nextcloud/providers Here they show all the public instances, but you can obviously host your own&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;org-074a33f9ba&quot;&gt;Google Playstore&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fdroid is a libre software focused app store for phones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# * Troler Recommendations# Android Auto# Android OS# - Ubuntu Touch# # Android TV# # Calendar# - Simple Calendar# # Cardboard# # Chrome# - Firefox# # Chrome Enterprise# # Chromebook# - Thinkpad# # Chromecast# # Connected Home# # Contacts# - Simple Contacts# # Digital Wellbeing# - GNU care# # Docs# - LibreOffice# # Drive# - NextCloud# # Earth# # Exposure Notifications# # Finance# # Forms# # Gboard# # Gmail# - Matthewevan.xyz# # Google Alerts# # Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture# # Google Assistant# # Google Authenticator# # Google Chat# # Google Classroom# # Google Duo# - Simple Dialer# # Google Expeditions# # Google Family Link# # Google Fi# # Google Files# - NextCloud# # Google Find My Device# # Google Fit# # Google Flights# # Google Fonts# - Simple Fonts# # Google Groups# # Google Home App# # Google Input Tools# # Google Lens# # Google Meet# # Google One# - NextCloud# # Google Pay# # Google Photos# - Simple Gallery# # Google Play# - F-Droid# # Google Play Books# # Google Play Games# # Google Play Pass# # Google Play Protect# # Google Podcasts# - AntennaPod# # Google Shopping# # Google Street View# # Google TV# # Google Tasks# # Google Workspace# # Hangouts# # Keep# # Maps# - OpenStreet Maps# # Messages# # News# # PhotoScan# # Pixel# # Pixel Buds# # Pixelbook# # Scholar# # Search# # Sheets# # Sites# # Slides# # Snapseed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Stadia# # Tilt Brush# # Translate# # Travel# # Voice# # Waze# # Wear OS by Google# # YouTube# - Invidious# # YouTube Kids# # YouTube Music# # YouTube TV# # YouTube VR                                                                                                                          # * Ayyzee Recommendations# Android OS# - Ubuntu Touch# - replicant# # Android TV# - Kodi# - Jellyfin# # Calendar# - Simple Calendar# # Cardboard# - VRCadia# # Chrome# - Firefox# # Chrome Enterprise# # Chromebook# - Thinkpad# - FrameWork# - Librem 15# - System76# # Chromecast# - Raspberry Pi# # Connected Home# - Home Assistant (Open Source Not 100% libre)# # Contacts# - Simple Contacts# # Digital Wellbeing# - GNU care# # Docs# - LibreOffice# # Drive# - NextCloud# - OWNCLOUD# - SFTP# # Earth# - KDE Marble# # Exposure Notifications# # Finance# # Forms# - Nextcloud forms# # Gboard# - FlorisyBoard# # Gmail# - Matthewevan.xyz# # Google Alerts# - notify-send 🤣# # Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture# # Google Assistant# - Home assistant# # Google Authenticator# - andOTP# # Google Chat# - Matrix# # Google Classroom# - Jitsi# # Google Duo# - Simple Dialer# # Google Expeditions# # Google Family Link# # Google Fi# # Google Files# - NextCloud# # Google Find My Device# - Don&amp;#39;t misplace or lose your device# # Google Fit# - Pen and paper diary# # Google Flights# # Google Fonts# - Simple Fonts# # Google Groups# # Google Home App# # Google Input Tools# # Google Lens# # Google Meet# - Jitsi# # Google One# - NextCloud Hub# # Google Pay# # Google Photos# - Simple Gallery# # Google Play# - F-Droid# # Google Play Books# # Google Play Games# # Google Play Pass# # Google Play Protect# - AppArmor# - SE-Linux# # Google Podcasts# - AntennaPod# # Google Shopping# # Google Street View# # Google TV# # Google Tasks# # Google Workspace# # Hangouts# # Keep# # Maps# - OpenStreet Maps# # Messages# # News# # PhotoScan# # Pixel# # Pixel Buds# # Pixelbook# # Scholar# # Search# # Sheets# # Sites# # Slides# # Snapseed# - GIMP# - RAWTHERAPEE# # Stadia# - VNC 🤣# # Tilt Brush# # Translate# # Travel# # Voice# # Waze# # Wear OS by Google# # YouTube# - Invidious# - Newpipe# # YouTube Kids# # YouTube Music# # YouTube TV# # YouTube VR&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
